《闪电侠》上季回顾
Last season on "The Flash"...
爱瑞丝·韦斯特
Iris West,
-你愿意嫁给我吗  -愿意
- Will you marry me? - Yes.
我已经不再是凯特琳了
I'm not Caitlin anymore.
-你也不是冰霜杀手  -不是
- You're not Killer Frost. - I'm not.
是别的
I'm something else,
我需要想清楚是什么  自己想清楚
and I need to figure out what that is on my own.
塞西尔·霍尔顿
Cecile Horton,
我爱你
I love you.
绝对不是一个缺口
That is definitely not a breach.
神速力不稳定
The Speed Force is unbalanced.
-这是神速力监狱  -没有囚犯
- This is Speed Force Prison. - Without a prisoner...
-它会不稳定  -我们要怎么阻止它
- It goes unstable. - How do we stop this?
我叫爱瑞丝·韦斯特
My name is Iris West,
我本来应该嫁给现今世上速度最快的那个人
and I was supposed to marry the fastest man alive,
但半年前  他离开了
but six months ago, he left.
巴里  是时候了
Barry, it's time.
巴里
Barry.
这不公平
This isn't fair.
我们应该有个美好的结局
We were supposed to have our happy ending.
我准备好做爱瑞丝·韦斯特·艾伦了
I'm ready to be Iris West-Allen.
你永远都会是的
And you always will be.
但你还需要继续生活
But you have to keep living your life, okay?
继续奔跑  为了我
Keep running, for me.
答应我你会继续跑下去  爱瑞丝
Promise me you'll run, Iris.
我答应你
I promise.
我答应他会跑下去
I promised him I'd run,
所以这就是过去半年来我一直在做的事
so that's what I've been doing these last six months,
以最快的速度跑
running as fast as I can.
我找不到她  西斯科
I can't find her, Cisco.
我得多锻炼了
Well, I gotta work out more.
她跑得太快了
She's really stepped up her game.
那我们也要加速  我看不见她
Then let's turn up ours. I don't have eyes on her.
-爱瑞丝  -收到  交给我
- Iris? - Copy, I'm on it.
正在找
Looking...
-发现她了  -然后呢
- Got her. - And?
-躲起来[鸭子]  -我没看见鸭子
- Duck! - I don't see no duck.
躲躲猫
Peekaboo.
只警告你们这一次
Your only warning, boys.
别管闲事
Stay back.
-她是让我们躲一下  -是的  难以相信
- She meant the other duck. - Yeah, I cannot believe
你竟然以为她是说鸭子
you actually thought she meant a duck duck.
她在哪  爱瑞丝
Where is she, Iris?
她去了楔石城大桥
She's headed for the Keystone Bridge.
如果她离开了本市  那就永远找不到她了
If she gets out of the city, we're gonna lose her for good.
你们必须现在阻止她
You guys have to stop her now.
这次我一定会抓到她
Oh, I'm gonna catch her this time.
我讨厌瞬移女
I hate teleporters.
三座
Three...
她每次跳跃间隔两座楼
She jumps every third rooftop.
热信号
西斯科  她下一次会跳到布鲁姆塔
Cisco, she's gonna jump to the Broome Tower.
-等她落地时抓住她  -好的
- When she lands, stop her. - On it.
-老爸  你去楼下等他们  -收到
- Dad, meet them at the bottom. - Copy.
-沃利  -我知道该怎么做
- Wally... - I know what to do.
来吧
Come on.
躲躲猫
Peekaboo-yah!
就像是《杀出洛杉矶》中一样
Dead Bang, fellas.
看哪
Look at that.
我们抓住她了
We got her.
闪 电 侠
第四季
第一集
我为我们感到骄傲
I'm so proud of us.
我们干得很漂亮  震波小队
That was a good hustle out there, Team Vibe.
是闪电小子小队  不过谢谢你
It's Team Kid Flash, but thank you.
好了  现在还不是庆祝的时候
Okay, not your finest hour, gentlemen.
你看我干嘛
What are you looking at me for?
是我把她放倒的
I was the one to put her down.
而且沃利和我给他提供了很大帮助
And Wally and I helped him out with the assist.
经典的动作
Classic maneuver.
是的  和我们预期的一模一样
Yeah, it actually went exactly as we planned.
完全按照我们的预期
Exactly as we planned.
如果你不相信我们  问问乔
You don't believe us, ask Joe.
乔  跟她说是不是跟预期的完全一样
Joe, go ahead and tell her how this went exactly as we planned.
瞬移女正中了我们的圈套
Peek-a-Boo fell right into our trap.
-我不说  -而且我们也没有
- I'm not doing that. - And we aren't exactly
按照我们以前的速率抓坏人
catching bad guys at our old rate.
过去半年里  我们要抓的超能力者中
One out of every three metas that we've fought
有三分之一都跑掉了
in the last six months has escaped.
暂时是这样
Temporarily, yes,
但是闪电小子小队会处理的
but Team Kid Flash is on the case.
儿子  我很爱你
Son, I love you,
但是没人觉得这个名字好听
but ain't nobody feeling Team Kid Flash.
感觉  音节太多了
It's, like, too many syllables.
好了  各位  少拌嘴吧
Okay, guys, maybe a little less fooling around
多干点实事
and a little more taking things seriously.
保护这座城市是我们的责任  对吧
It's up to us to protect this city, right?
因为没有别人可以依靠了
Because there is no one else.
沃利  你去一下极速实验室吧
Wally, why don't you go to the Speed Lab?
我给你设计了一个新的模拟训练
I've programmed a new training simulation for you.
-只需要四个小时  -四个小时
- It should only take four hours. - Four-- what?
不是吧  今晚的家庭聚餐怎么办
No, what about family dinner tonight?
训练听起来很棒
You know what, training sounds amazing.
好  家里见  老大
Okay. See ya at home, boss.
西斯科  你要不要
Cisco, you wanna...
和我说说你在想什么
share what you're thinking?
我在想如果我们不是少了一个人
I'm thinking it would be a lot better off
情况会好很多
if we weren't one man down.
我只是还有几个箱子要搬过来
I only have a couple more boxes to bring over.
车库或是地下室里已经没有空间了
We have no more room in the garage or the basement.
对  或者我们可以扔掉一些你的东西
Right-- or, we could just get rid of some more of your stuff.
-比如说什么  -宝贝  你真的需要
- Like what? - Like, babe, do you really need
那些发臭的旧唱片吗
all the smelly old records in there?
-塞西尔  -唱片
- Oh, Cecile... - Records?
你是说我的古董爵士黑胶碟藏品吗
You mean my vintage jazz LP collection...
我过去三十年来
That I painstakingly
煞费苦心  精心收集的那些藏品吗
and carefully collected over the last 30 years?
-不是吧  -那些都是我心头好  宝贝
- Really? - Those are my loves, babe.
我死的时候那些唱片要和我一起下葬的
They're going in the coffin with me when I die.
也许我们现在就可以把唱片埋起来
Okay, maybe we could bury them now,
将来你可以直接加入它们的行列
and you can just join them at a later date.
-你还真能说笑  -嗯
- Oh, you got jokes? - Yeah.
你很幸运我已经把钥匙给了你
You lucky I already gave you the key,
因为我要开始重新考虑同居的事
because I'm starting to rethink this whole move-in thing.
-你不会的  -我不会的
- No, you're not. - No, I'm not.
你不会的
No, you're not...
因为你爱我
'Cause you love me.
不如我去煮几杯咖啡吧
Why don't I go make some coffee?
当然了
Obvious.
那个啥
Okay, so,
自从朱利安搬回伦敦后
ever since Julian moved back to London,
中城警局取证室一直人手不足
they have been short-staffed in the crime lab at CCPD,
而我一直在搪塞辛格
and I've been stalling Singh with this whole story of
和他说巴里在捷克共和国休假
Barry being on sabbatical in the Czech Republic...
他们想找人代替他
And they wanna hire someone to replace him.
应该的  他们需要人帮忙
Yeah, they should. They need the help.
-巴里不会回来了  -这你不能确定
- Barry's not coming back, so... - You don't know that.
我确定
Yes, I do.
亲爱的
Sweetheart...
你现在在尖端科研实验室带领沃利和西斯科
I'm very proud of you for taking the lead
我为你感到骄傲
with Wally and Cisco at S.T.A.R. Labs,
也让你有自己的空间
and I let you have your space,
好让你有时间去处理巴里的事
so that you'd have time to deal with what happened.
爸  我没事
Dad, I'm fine, okay?
可我不是  我们失去他了  爱瑞丝
I'm not. We lost him, Iris.
我的儿子  你的一切
My son, your everything.
爸  你想我怎样
Dad, what do you want me to do?
一天到晚哭作一团吗
Curl up in a ball and cry all day?
我做不到
I can't do that.
巴里叫我坚强起来  我现在很坚强
Barry told me to be strong. I'm being strong.
HR死的时候  我们办了丧礼
When H.R. died, we had a funeral.
我们讲述了他的一生
We spoke about his life.
也许我们也该为巴里这么做
Maybe we should do the same thing for Barry,
允许大家哀悼
give us all permission to grieve.
那我们要埋葬什么  爸
And what are we gonna bury, Dad?
实验室里的一件空壳战衣吗
An empty suit in the lab?
帮我谢谢塞西尔邀请我吃晚餐
You know what, thank Cecile for dinner.
我要走了
I'm gonna get going, okay?
沃利   西斯科
Wally? Cisco?
有情况
We're up.
各位  什么情况
Guys? What are we looking at?
我的神啊
Holy Ronin.
是个武士
It's a Samurai.
谁会说日语
Anybody speak Japanese?
你想怎样
告诉我他刚才说的不是日语吧
Tell me he did not just speak Japanese.
我会的东西可多了
I can do things.
我们并不想伤害你
闪电侠
The Flash.
就站在你眼前呢  兄弟
Yeah, you're looking at him, pal.
你不是闪电侠  你不是最厉害的
You're not The Flash. You're not the best.
叫闪电侠来见我
Bring me The Flash...
我觉得话里还有"不然"
I'm sensing an "Or else"
不然你的城市就完蛋了
Or else your city falls.
闪电侠是不会来的
The Flash ain't coming.
不仅如此  三船
Furthermore, Mifune,
我们要你把剑放回剑鞘里
we're gonna need you to sheath that sword
以免伤到人
before somebody gets hurt,
比如说伤到你自己
somebody like you, for instance,
因为你现在面对的可是厉害角色
'cause you're up against some bad hombres,
你认为你要怎么对抗我们
and what do you think you're gonna do against us
就用一把剑吗
with a sword?
你们没事吧
You guys okay?
那把到底是什么剑
What the hell kinda sword is that?
你们只有一天时间
You have one day.
如果闪电侠不来见我
If The Flash does not face me,
中城就要灭亡
Central City dies.
差不多六个月没看到闪电侠的身影
The Flash hasn't been seen in almost six months,
即时新闻
让我们猜测
leaving us to speculate
谁能把我们从最新的威胁中拯救出来
what can save us from this newest threat.
城里还有其他的超级英雄
There are other superheroes in this town.
还有你刚刚的那位黑泽明兄弟
Yeah, and your boy, Kurosawa, over there
把我们像布偶一样吹飞
blew us away like ragdolls
耍着他那逆神剑
performing his reverse Excalibur.
咱们以前可没面对过这种敌人
We haven't faced anything like this before.
你觉得他为什么只想要闪电侠
Why do you think he only wanted The Flash?
他说想要和最好的战斗
He said he wants to fight the best.
他威胁要毁掉城市
He's threatening to destroy the city.
-你觉得他能做到吗  -我说能
- Do we think he can do it? - I say yes.
那他就会和闪电侠对战
Then he has to fight The Flash.
可他不在啊
Who isn't here?
如果他在呢
What if he was?
爱瑞丝  你之前也说过
Iris, you said it yourself.
就我们几个保证城市的安全
Just us trying to keep the city safe,
已经是快到极限了
we're barely getting it done.
而这家伙  他可不是玩的
And this guy, he's no joke.
如果我们不请出闪电侠  那就有大麻烦了
If we don't offer up The Flash, there's gonna be serious damage.
会有人因此而死  而罪责在我们
People are gonne die, and that's gonna be on us.
我们需要把巴里找回来
We need to bring Barry back.
西斯科  我们不能
Cisco, we can't.
如果巴里出来  神速力监狱就没了
If Barry comes out, the Speed Force Prison goes--
它会变得不稳定
It becomes unstable.
那会毁了整个城市  甚至全世界
It could destroy the city, the whole world.
我们就是要防止这种事发生
Which is exactly what we're trying to prevent.
如果我能解决那问题呢
What if I can solve that?
-在24小时内吗  -是的
- In the next 24 hours? - Yes!
各位  我一直在搞这个
Guys, I've been working on this.
做了多久
For how long?
自从他离开之后
Since the night he left.
-西斯科  -我有帮手
- Cisco? - I've had help.
我一直在资讯哈里和蒂娜
I've consulted with Harry and--and Tina
还有特蕾西 还有费利西蒂  还有柯蒂斯
and Tracy and Felicity and Curtis,
然后我觉得我已经找到了
and I'm pretty sure I figured out a way
释放巴里然后稳定神速力监狱的方法
to stabilize the Speed Force Prison and free Barry
避免在城市里再释放一次闪电风暴
without unleashing another lightning storm on the city.
我只需要一些东西
I just need a couple more things.
-也许我们应该配合  -不
- Maybe we should. - No.
你一直在研究这件事多久了
You've been working on this for how long
就这么瞒着我们
and you never told us?
我不想在没确定之前说什么
I didn't wanna say anything until I was certain.
你确定神速力
Are you certain that the Speed Force
不会带走沃利来替代他吗
won't take Wally in his place?
你能确定可以及时关闭它
Are you certain that you can even close it
不让它把中城切成两半吗
before it rips Central City in two?
你确定巴里还活着吗
Are you certain that Barry is even still alive?
他肯定活着
He's gotta be.
爱瑞丝  在这么些人里
Iris, you, of all people,
只有你不该这么不支持的啊
how can you not be in on this?
因为巴里走了
Because Barry is gone.
这是我们唯一能够确定的
That is the only thing any of us can be certain about.
现在  让我们做些力所能及的想办法
Now, let's do what we can do to come up with a plan
干掉这个武士
to take out this Samurai.
好吗
Okay?
-好吗  -好的
- Okay? - Okay...
不过我需要些咖啡
But I'm gonna need some coffee.
你好
Hello.
我的天  选择真多
My, what a selection.
你有什么推荐的吗
You got any recommendations?
有  去别的地方喝
Yeah, drink somewhere else.
你需要些什么
What can I get you?
我想要些甜美的
Let's go with something sweet
但是非常强劲
but deceptively strong
加一大堆冰
with lots of ice.
秀兰·邓波儿  马上就好
Shirley Temple, coming right up.
这么好的女孩  两个博士学位一个哲学博士
What is a nice girl with two doctorates and a PHD
在这样的老鼠窝里做什么呢
doing in a rat's nest like this one?
工作  你怎么找到我的
Working. How'd you find me?
因为我电脑技术好
'Cause I'm great with computers,
而且我有自己的卫星  你自己想吧
and I have my own satellite. You do the math.
-你用震波找的我  -我用了振波  是的
- You Vibed me. - I Vibed you, yes.
你比上次咱们见面时少了点冰霜
You're looking a lot less frosty than the last time I saw you.
你说你不是她  但你也不是凯特琳
You said you weren't her, but you weren't Caitlin either.
就只是我  西斯科  我只是凯特琳
It's just me, Cisco. I'm just Caitlin.
你是怎么做到的
How'd you do it?
你想要什么
What do you want?
先来个劲大的  作为开始
Well, a stiffer drink, for starters.
如果你回归正常了  我想知道
If you're back to normal, I have to know,
你为什么不会到我们这里
why didn't you come back to us?
好  我懂的  没事
Okay, I get it. That's fine.
我不会逼你回答的
I'm not gonna make you answer that.
但我们真的需要你
But we really could've used you.
巴里还困在神速力里呢
Barry's still stuck in the Speed Force?
你知道这事
You knew about that?
我要把他弄出来  我需要你帮助
I'm gonna get him out, but I need your help.
一切都好吗
Everything okay?
-一切都好  -是啊  好着呢  伙计
- Everything's fine. - Yeah, everything's great, pal.
你介意吗  我在和女士说话呢
Do you mind? I'm talking to the lady.
我肯定你能在这里找到别人
I'm sure there's someone else you can find in here
来同情你错误的人生选择
to commiserate with over poor life choices.
谢谢
Thank you.
听着  我想出办法救巴里了
Look, I figured out how to save Barry,
但是没有你我办不到
but I can't do it without you.
你看到今天出现的那个武士了吗
Did you see that Samurai that showed up today?
是的
Yes.
他威胁说要炸毁中城
He's threatening to blow up the city,
我们需要巴里阻止他
and we need Barry to stop him.
帮帮我们  拜托
So help us out, please?
凯特琳
Caitlin?
我一小时后下班
My shift's over in an hour.
美女  我等得及
Girl, I got time.
这酒不错
Oh, this is good.
还有什么是你做不了的吗
Is there anything you can't do?
显然是放下过去
Move on, apparently.
等着我们  你就要回家了  兄弟
Hang tight. You're coming home, buddy.
西斯科  能把知更鸟卫星调出来吗
Hey, Cisco, can you pull up the Mockingbird satellite?
我们要追踪这个日本武士
We're tracking down this Samurai.
西斯科
Cisco?
沃利
Wally?
定位尖端科研实验室箱车
箱车信号获取
两位韦斯特先生  你们好
Mr. West, Mr. West.
我们在这儿干什么  西斯科
So, what are we doing out here, Cisco?
这地方看上去很合适
It seemed an appropriate venue.
-我们在这儿交过好运  -我们为什么需要好运
- We've had good luck here before. - Why do we need good luck?
因为我们要把巴里带回来
Because we're bringing Barry back.
西斯科  爱瑞丝说了
Cisco, Iris said--
我知道她说了什么  乔
I know what Iris said, Joe.
我也知道巴里说过他离开后
I also know Barry said everyone would look to me
所有人都要依靠我
after he was gone.
所以听我的
So look to me.
我们四个人  可以做到
Four of us, we can do this.
四个人是什么意思
What do you mean the four of us?
-乔  -没事的
- Hi, Joe. - It's okay.
她又回来了  我们的凯特琳
She's Caitlin again, our Caitlin.
她是过来帮我们的
She's here to help us.
你们怎么说
So, what do you say?
你最好是对的
You better be right.
当然
I am.
乔  我知道我做什么都无法弥补
Joe, I know that I can never make up
对你和塞西尔造成的伤害
for the things that I did to you, to Cecile.
我只希望
I just hope--
只希望有一天你会原谅我
I just hope that one day you can forgive me.
抱抱
Come here.
-今天咱们把所有人都带回家吧  -没问题
- Let's bring everybody home today, okay? - You got it.
我们怎么做才能把巴里带回来
So how are we gonna bring
又不把世界炸出一个洞呢
Barry back without blowing a hole in the, uh, world?
本着带回老朋友的精神
Ha! In the spirit of bringing back old friends,
我带来了神速力火箭炮
may I present the Speed Force bazooka.
我做了一些小调整
I made a few slight modifications,
正如索罗船长会说的
as Captain Solo would say.
《星球大战》人物
凯特琳和我昨天花了整晚
Caitlin and I spent all of last night
解决问题  微调了夸克球体
working out some kinks, fine-tuning the Quark Sphere.
-什么  -夸克球体
- What? - The Quark Sphere,
充满了巴里特殊的遗传标记
filled with Barry's unique genetic marker,
并被编程追踪他特别的DNA
and programmed to track his specific DNA,
运用了神速力的电流
using the electrical current of the Speed Force.
一旦我们追踪到巴里  把他拉出来
Once we track Barry and we pull him out,
这个夸克球体会瞒骗神速力
the Quark Sphere will trick the Speed Force
-让它以为巴里仍在那里  -沃利
- into thinking he's still there. - Hey, Wally,
可以把那个放在路标塔中间吗
can you put that on the center pylon?
-就绪  -咱们把小伙伴带回家吧
- Ready. - Let's bring our boy home.
夸克物质在扫瞄电流
Quark Matter scanning electrical current.
在他的位置三角定位夸克物质
Triangulating Quark Matter on his location.
雷达跟踪上什么了
I've got a lock on something.
是他
It's him.
It's him!
趁现在  西斯科
Now, Cisco!
系统失败
不敢相信你们背着我这么做
I can't believe you did this behind my back.
因为你肯定会阻止我们
You would've tried to stop us.
因为这是浪费时间
Because it was a waste of time.
没道理的  应该起作用的
I don't understand. This should've worked.
或者你会害了我们所有人
Or you could've killed us all.
我不知道  爱瑞丝  我以为我们可以做到
I don't know, Iris. I think we were pretty close.
你说什么  我们
I'm sorry, "We"?
过去这半年你去哪里了
Where have you been the last six months again?
她只是想要帮忙
She was only trying to help.
大伙们  我们应该专心于阻止日本武士
Look, guys, we need to concentrate on stopping this Samurai
毁灭城市  而不是把巴里找回来
who's trying to destroy the city, not on Barry.
所以你有好点子吗
Dude, what is your deal?
听上去你根本不想让他回来
It's like you don't even want him back.
塞西尔  我一会回过来可以吗
Cecile, can I call you back in a minute?
我们正在处理事情
We're in the middle of something here.
什么
What?
中城警局
州警察在常春藤城外的112号国道
State police picked him up on the 112
-发现他的  -那有300英里远
- outside of Ivy City. - That's 300 miles away.
对  有一个警察是楔石城的老人
Yeah, one of the cops is a Keystone vet.
-认出了他  -我就知道有用的
- Recognized him. - I knew it would work.
我就知道
I knew it.
你得做个心理准备
You should prepare yourselves.
巴里
Barry?
Barry...
诺拉不该在这里
Nora shouldn't be here.
你妈妈不在这儿  巴里  我是
Your mom isn't here, Barry. It's--
是我  爱瑞丝
it's me, Iris.
你回家了
You're home.
法官大人  我是无辜的
Your Honor, I'm innocent.
这不是我干的  我没有杀人
I didn't do this. I didn't kill anyone.
你能听到星星的歌唱吗
Can you hear the stars singing?
韵律和谐  节拍准确  每时每刻不停歇
Rhyming, chiming, timing every hour, every minute.
是你说这城市是安全的
You said the city was safe,
你说这里没有剩余的危险
that there was no residual danger,
但这不是真的
but that's not true.
那晚所发生的事...
What really happened that night--
这城市确实是安全的
The city is safe.
是你救了这座城市  你救了我们所有人
You saved it. You saved us all.
星星在融化  像冰激凌
Stars melting like ice cream,
梦幻  微光
dream, gleam.
一切看起来都...
Nothing seems--
诺拉不该来这儿
Nora shouldn't be here.
我觉得他不只是受冲击那么简单
I'm guessing this isn't just shock.
受冲击是由血压降低造成的
Shock results from a drop in blood pressure.
他问题出在神经上
This is neurological.
这是个研究物理的全新视角
It's a whole new way of looking at physics.
这会改变我们对所有事物的看法
It will change the way that we think about everything,
从一颗原子
from a single atom
到整个银河
to an entire galaxy.
天
God!
星星太吵了
Stars so loud.
吵  草  恼
Loud, cloud, proud.
我和爸爸都没事
Dad and I are both okay.
我们会没事的
We're gonna be fine.
我就是不能确定自己是否和你一样  奥利弗
I'm just not sure I'm like you, Oliver.
我们得马上带他回尖端科研实验室
We need to get him back to S.T.A.R. Labs now.
诊断结果如何
What's the diagnosis?
他有大脑损伤之类的吗
Does he have brain damage or something?
其实他健康得吓人
He's actually scary healthy.
他的神经递质传输速度
His neurotransmitters are functioning at
是正常人的五倍
five times the normal speed.
-那是怎么回事  -我有两个想法
- Then what's wrong? - I have two theories.
一  他正遭受某种杂语症的困扰
One is that he's suffering from a form of schizophasia.
患病者混淆了各个词语的意思
That's where you assign the wrong definitions to words.
所以从他的角度理解
So, from his perspective,
所有的胡说都不是胡说吗
all that nonsense he's saying makes sense?
可惜我们没有翻译器
It's too bad we don't have a translator.
是没有  但我们可以造一个
No, but we can make one.
如果他的大脑处在杂语症状态
If his brain's schizophastic
而这些符号代表着不同的词
and these symbols represent different words,
他可能是在向我们传递信息
he could be sending us a message,
我们只要找出正确的算法解密就好了
and we just need the right algorithm to decrypt it.
你刚说你有两个想法  另一个是什么
You said you had two theories. What's the other one?
我们知道神速力是存在于时空之外的
We know that the Speed Force exists beyond space and time.
对我们来说  巴里在那里只待了六个月
To us, Barry was only in there for six months,
但对他来说  可能已经过了一万年
but to him, it could've been 10,000 years.
与世隔绝了这么久
All that time in isolation,
很可能患上痴呆症
it could've caused dementia.
他的神智可能就剩这么一点了
That may be all of him that's left.
那我们该怎么判断是哪种情况呢
So how do we find out which one it is?
我可以减少镇静剂  让他醒来
I could decrease the sedative, wake him up.
我觉得我找到完美对应的那首歌了
I think I've got the perfect song for that.
你确定这合适吗
Are you sure this is appropriate?
嗯  这是个幸运符
Yeah. It's a good luck charm.
以前就管用过
I mean, it worked before.
上次他是昏迷
Last time, he was in a coma,
又没有陷入泛时空超维空间里
not a pan-temporal extra dimension.
那听着嘎嘎姐的歌醒来应该不会太吓人
Well, waking up to Gaga shouldn't seem too freaky.
巴里
Hey, Barry.
是我  西斯科
It's me, Cisco,
外号震波
AKA Vibe,
也是你一辈子的好朋友
BKA your BFF.
好了  哥们
Yeah. Hey, buddy.
你不在的时候  我们给你做了套新行头
While you were gone, I made you a new suit.
你想穿出去转转吗
Do you wanna take it out for a spin?
星星在陨落
The stars are raining.
在枯竭
Draining.
痛苦  还太早
Paining. Too soon.
以后再说吧
I think maybe later.
不用了  谢谢  我不饿
No, thank you. I'm not hungry.
他没干那些事
He didn't do those things.
他没有伤害我妈妈  那晚我也在
He didn't hurt my mom. I was there that night.
当时有个人  计划
There was a man, plan.
没有计划
No plan.
我们得买更多尿布了
We're gonna need more diapers.
尿布
Diapers.
你继续画  哥们
You keep drawing, buddy.
你继续画  我会解出来的
You keep drawing. I'm gonna figure this out.
-凯特琳  -我不知道
- Caitlin... - I don't know.
各位  能让我们单独待一会儿吗
Guys, can I get the room for a second?
巴里
Barry...
我不知道你听不听得到我
I don't know if you can hear me,
也不知道你是不是想传送什么信息
or if you're trying to send us a message somehow.
我做了你让我去做的事
Hey, I did what you told me to.
我一直向前奔跑  不停前进
I kept running, I kept moving forward,
因为我知道一旦停下回头
because I knew that if I stopped to look back,
我就会想起来  你再也不在我的身后了
then I would remember that you weren't behind me anymore.
这对我来说太艰难了
And it's been so hard.
当西斯科说他能让你回来时
And when Cisco said that he could bring you back,
我不知道该怎么办
you know I didn't know what to think.
如果失败了  或者你已经死了呢
What if it didn't work? What if you were dead?
那我就会再一次失去你
I mean, I thought it would be like losing you all over again.
但我没想过会像现在这样
I never imagined this, though.
我不知道该怎样面对这样的你
I don't know what I would do if this is all that's left of you,
如果我所认识并深爱的那个人
if this is all that's left of the amazing man that I know
变成了现在的样子
and love.
回到我身边吧
Please come back to me.
告诉我  你依然是我的巴里
Tell me you're still my Barry.
伙计们
Guys?
巴里  巴里  停下
Barry! Barry, stop!
把他关到管道监狱里
Breach him to the pipeline!
他太快了
He's too fast!
在等别人吗
Expecting someone else?
我们得把他关在密闭牢房里
We need to get him in a containment cell
以免再次发生
before he does that again.
黑武士回来了
Samurai's back.
或者说是蠢武士
More like Samurai jackass.
那只是个雏形
Nope, that's a rough draft.
还没到一整天
It hasn't even been a full day yet.
他说如果找不到闪电侠就要摧毁城市
He said he'd level the city if we didn't bring in The Flash.
那就如他所愿
Well, let's give him what he asked for.
你想和我对决
You wanted me...
我来了
Here I am.
你不是闪电侠
You're not The Flash.
沃利
Wally!
如果今晚我见不到真正的闪电侠
If I don't get the real Flash by nightfall,
我就毁灭这座城市
this city comes down.
我多久能恢复
How long till I can get back out there?
沃利  他刺穿了你的腓骨
Wally, he sliced right through your fibula.
如果你不是一个极速者
If you weren't a speedster,
现在就该截肢了
I'd be amputating your leg right now.
到底多久
Okay, how long?
四五个小时吧
Four to five hours?
我们没那么多时间
We don't have that kinda time.
我没事的
You know what, I'm fine.
孩子  孩子
Son--son, son...
你已经竭尽全力了
You've done everything you can do.
放松
Relax.
-有好消息吗  -还没
- Any luck? - No, not yet.
电脑上还是一堆乱码
The computer keeps telling me it's random gibberish.
-或许就是这样  -不会的
- Maybe it is. - No, it's not.
巴里想告诉我们什么  我确定
Barry's trying to send us a message. I know it.
他在神速力中待了那么久
I mean, he spent all this time in the Speed Force.
或许他知道了
Maybe now he knows the answers to
生命  宇宙以及万物的终极答案
life, the universe, and everything.
你觉得他的画符
So you think all this crazy writing
是在告诉我们终极问题的答案吗
is Barry's way of telling us 42?
没错
Yes, exactly.
我有没有说  我有多想念你
Have I mentioned how much I miss having you around?
我不会放弃的
I'm gonna keep working on this....
你有什么头绪吗
unless you have any ideas.
没有  对我来说和希腊语一样
Nope, it's all Greek to me.
伟大的恺撒大帝
Great Caesar's Ghost.
这个分析系统
This analysis is based on
是基于单表代替密码的
a monoalphabetic substitution cipher,
可如果是多字母呢
but what if it's polyalphabetic?
如果像希腊语一样呢
What if it's-- it's like Greek?
如果这些符号是一个独特的字母表呢
Like the symbols are unique alphabet?
太棒了
Excelsior!
-怎么了  -西斯科找到方法了
- What is it? - Cisco figured it out.
他知道如何破解巴里的符号了
He figured out how to crack Barry's code.
-是吗  是什么意思  -稍等一下
- You did? What does it say? - Hold on one sec.
还在加载  加油
It's loading. Come on...
加载  加载  加载  是说...
Loading, loading, loading, loading--and it says...
"这房子太差劲了"
"This house is bitchin'"
"This house is bitchin'"?
-不像是巴里会说的话  -没错
- That doesn't sound like Barry. - No.
是的  确实不像
No. No, it doesn't.
因为根本不是
That's 'cause it's not.
这里面不会有一个科学怪人吧
Don't tell me you have Frankenstein under there.
那是巴里的新战衣
It's Barry's new suit,
可是现在看来
although right now,
我觉得这完全是在浪费时间
I'm having trouble seeing it as anything other than a waste of time.
-西斯科...  -我知道
- Cisco... - I know.
我该听你的话
I should've listened to you.
承认巴里不是在和我们沟通
Barry was never trying to communicate with us,
当我相信不是这样
but I believed it.
我非常相信
I really did.
我只是觉得如果我坚定地相信
Sometimes, I feel like if I believe in something hard enough,
它就会发生
that'll make it real.
你知道最糟糕的地方吗
You know what the worst part is?
我这样做不是为了拯救这座城市
I didn't do it to save the city.
我是为了...
I did it because it...
给自己一个理由把他找回来
gave me an excuse to bring him back.
是因为我想念我的朋友
I did it because I missed my friend.
好多了
Much better.
你亲口说过
You said it yourself.
她在自寻死路
She goes looking for danger.
本以为帮他梳洗
I thought cleaning him up
会让我好过一点  但是...
would make me feel better, but...
是啊
Yeah.
他越像原来的他
The more he looks like his old self,
越告诉我他有多么迷失自我
the more it reminds you how lost he is.
你要相信  一切都会好的
You have to believe that things can get better.
每个问题都有一个答案
There is an answer for every question.
我不知道怎么回答  爸爸
I don't think I know how to anymore, Dad.
我懂这种感觉  我也曾受此煎熬
I know that feeling. I was struggling with it too.
但我后来明白了
But I figured it out.
-怎样明白的  -做礼拜
- How? - Church.
从我小时候起你就没去过教堂啊
You haven't gone to church since I was a kid.
我知道
I know.
塞西尔建议如此  她觉得那会有帮助
Cecile suggested it, thought it would help.
但我发誓
But I swear,
神父布道当中那句
one of the priest's homilies,
就好像  就好像是为我而写
it was like-- it was like he wrote it for me.
没有信心
"Strength means nothing
力量便什么也不是
without faith"
我开始明白
And I started realizing
我的力量没能让我停止去想
that my strength
萨维塔从我这儿夺走你
didn't stop me from thinking I lost you to Savitar,
以及我们再也见不到巴里了
or that we'd never see Barry again.
塞西尔提醒我要有信心
Cecile reminded me to have faith...
我相信了
and I believed.
可你们俩却成了这样
And here you two are.
你拥有能力  孩子
You got strength, baby girl.
你只需多一点信心
You just need a little faith.
乔  黑武士要求的24小时到了
Joe, Samurai's 24 hours are up.
我得走了
Gotta go.
来找我
Come get me.
我没见到闪电侠
I don't see The Flash.
我恐怕你得先设法应对我们
I'm afraid you're gonna have to make do with us.
爱瑞丝  停止射击
Iris! Hold your fire.
你想见闪电侠  抓了我
You want The Flash? Take me.
为什么
Why?
因为他会来救我
Because he'll come for me.
你
And how...
怎么知道
do you know this?
我相信
I believe.
爱瑞丝
Iris!
黑武士抓走了爱瑞丝
Hey! Samurai's got Iris.
-她自己主动被抓的  -什么
- She gave herself up to him. - What?
她为什么那么做
Why would she do that?
我们怎么救她
How do we get her back?
巴里  爱瑞丝有危险  她需要你的帮助
Barry! Iris is in trouble. She needs your help.
我怀疑克制使你成为
I doubt restraint is how you got to be
现在的你  游戏  方式  不可能
the man you are today, play, way, no way!
大路  小路
Highway, byway!
不要这样  孩子  别这样
Please, son. Please!
我愿意帮你  我会的
I wanna help you with all this, and I will,
但现在她需要我们的帮助
but right now she needs our help,
否则她会死的
or she's gonna die.
巴里  你听到我说的了吗  爱瑞丝要死了
Barry, did you hear what I said? Iris is gonna die!
巴里不见了
Barry's gone.
你知道还有什么不见了吗
You know what else is gone?
新战衣
The new suit.
发生了什么
What's happening?
闪电侠回来了
The Flash is back!
你看到他跑得有多快吗
Do you see how fast he's running?
-我从没有那么快过  -从没人有过
- I've never gone that fast. - No one has.
爱瑞丝  位置跟踪
黑武士要把爱瑞丝带到哪
Where is this Samurai taking Iris?
他们早已过了丹维尔
They're already way past Danville,
那只有平原和
and the only thing out there is the flatlands and...
和什么
And what?
武士
闪电侠
爱瑞丝
快呀  巴里  救下她
Come on, Barry, catch her.
闪电侠
The Flash,
欢迎回来
welcome home.
巴里
Barry...
你回到我身边了
You came back to me.
我永远在你身边
Always.
瞳孔对光的反应一致
Pupils are equally reactive to light.
你的生命体征太棒了
I mean, your vitals are amazing.
即使对有超能力的你来说也是非常健康
You're in perfect health, even for you.
我要取个尿样  只是为了确认一下
I--I'd like a urine sample, just to confirm,
但一切都很好
but everything looks great.
你可真喜欢尿
Man, you love urine.
你喜欢化验尿
You love the -- the testing of urine.
化验尿  你明白我的意思
The testing of the urine. You know what I meant.
你为什么一定要把科学毁了
Why do you have to ruin science?
你能回来真是太好了
It's good to have you back.
彼此彼此
Right back at ya.
很高兴你能回来
It's good to have you back.
-你感觉怎么样  -很好
- How you feeling? - I feel great.
感觉好极了
Yeah, I feel incredible.
我不知道  感觉好像是重生
I don't know, it feels like I've been reborn.
好吧  快神
Well, okay, speedy Jesus.
我是认真的
Seriously, though.
虽然我不愿意承认
I mean, it hurts me to admit it,
但你可能是史上最快的极速者
but you may be the fastest speedster ever.
你在神速力里呆了六个月
I mean, you were in the Speed Force for six months.
或许你吸收了它的能量
Maybe you were soaking up its energy?
可能吧
Maybe.
我不在的时候一切怎么样
How was everything while I was gone?
一切都酷毙了
Oh, yeah, it was-- it was really cool.
一切都在闪电小子队的控制之下
Team Kid Flash had everything under control, so...
那不是我们的名字
That's not our name.
但我们还有一些谜团要解决
But still, we have some mysteries left to solve,
比如会飞的黑武士机器人
like our flying Samurai robot...
机器人黑武士
Android Samurai.
机士  我们回来了  宝贝
Samur-oid. We back, baby!
有人造出这东西来
Yeah, someone created this,
肯定有其目的
and it must be for a reason.
"这房子太差劲了"这句话
Does the phrase, "this house is bitchin'"
能令你想起什么吗
mean anything to you?
不
No?
-该有吗  -不
- Should it? - No.
要知道你在"美丽大脑"状态时
Just know that when you were in your "Beautiful Mind" phase,
你毫不含糊地胡说八道
you were talking straight-up nonsense.
我不记得了
I don't remember any of that.
我最后的记忆是跟我妈去神速力
Last thing I remember was going into the Speed Force with my mom
拯救爱瑞丝
and then saving Iris.
你怎么知道爱瑞丝有麻烦的
So how'd you know Iris was in trouble?
我不知道
I don't know.
谢谢你带我回家
Well, thanks for bringing me home.
你太客气了
You're very welcome.
西斯科
Hey, Cisco,
谢谢你在我无法相信时选择相信
thanks for believing when I couldn't.
明天见  老板
We'll see you tomorrow, boss.
我知道我们还有一些没解决的问题
I know we left some questions unanswered,
但我想知道
but I have to know,
明天我们会见面吗
are we gonna see you tomorrow?
会的
Yeah, you will.
我们回来了  宝贝
We back, baby.
-你去哪了  -这不重要
- Where have you been? - Doesn't matter.
真的吗
Really?
告诉阿姆内特我要退出
Tell Amunet I'm out.
你要退出  斯诺  不行
You wanna quit, Snow? Doesn't work that way.
总之阿姆内特让你做什么你就做什么
You do what Amunet says for as long as she tells you.
不再是了
Not anymore.
别再来找我
Now leave me alone.
轮不到你说了算
You don't tell us what to do.
别逼我结霜
Don't make me frosty.
你不会喜欢结霜的我
You wouldn't like me when I'm frosty.
怎么了  脑袋冻住了吗
What's the matter? Brain freeze?
再碰我的手  我就把你的手冻住
Touch my hand again, and I'll freeze yours off,
可能还有你身体的其他部分
maybe some other parts too.
告诉阿姆内特我不干了
Tell Amunet I'm done.
别让你的啤酒变暖
Don't let your beer get warm.
娱乐时间开始了
Time to have some fun.
还没
Not yet.
不不  不不不不不
No, no. No, no, no, no, no.
不不不
No, no, no.
别再有下次
Not again.
累吗  要睡一下吗
Are you tired? Do you want to get some sleep?
不用  我感觉我已经睡了几个月
No, I feel like I've been asleep for months.
我无法独自一人在我们的床上睡觉
I, I couldn't bring myself to sleep in our bed alone.
甚至连看一眼也不行
I couldn't even look at that.
那段日子太难受了  巴里
It's been really hard, Barry.
我回来了
Hey, well, I'm back,
我再也不会离开你了
and I'm never going anywhere ever again.
我努力照你的话
I tried to keep going,
继续前进  继续战斗  继续奔跑
to keep fighting, to keep running, like you said.
你做到了
You did.
你让大家待在一起
You kept everyone together.
我为你感到很骄傲
I'm so proud of you, okay?
听起来像在说笑
Look, it sounds funny,
但也许这是种福气
but... maybe this was a blessing.
你离开半年是种福气吗
You being gone for six months was a blessing?
我无法告诉你我的感觉  爱瑞丝
I just--I--I can't tell you how I feel, Iris.
感觉像是我的人生不对的事
It's like, everything that was wrong in my life,
我过去的伤痛和错误
the pain of my past, my mistakes,
全都抹掉了
it's all just washed away,
我只看见你和我们
and all I see is you and us
还有我们的将来
and our future together.
爱瑞丝  一切都会好的
Iris, it's gonna be great.
中城需要闪电侠
Central City needs The Flash.
我会很快回来  我保证
I'll be right back, I promise.
黑武士尽了职责
The Samurai served its purpose.
十二世纪的日本封建时期
As in 12th century feudal Japan,
军人阶级有很大的权势
a time when the military class was powerful,
有一套系统的执行方式
the execution methodical,
跟我们一样
like ours.
闪电侠回归
成功了
Well, it worked.
闪电侠回到中城了
The Flash is back in Central City.
一切似乎都按计划进行
It appears things are going as planned.
毋庸置疑
As if there were any doubt.
我们下一步要怎么做
What's our next step?
我还在想
I'm thinking.